Daniel A. Pinedo

Operations & Strategy Management

**** 213.999.5619

@ daniel.pinedo@cgu.edu

% pinedo.org

SUMMARY

Manager specialized in people operations and business strategy. Experience in creating selection tools that incorporate machine-assisted decision-making. Leader that elicits focus, deep listening, and insights in colleague interactions. Background in research, evaluation, and statistical methods.

ABILITIES



Performance Monitoring & Evaluation



Coaching & Mentoring



Talent Research & Development



Talent Management



Nurturing Inclusive Culture



Operations & Strategy

EXPERIENCE

Associate Consultant

Accenture PLC, Talent Innovation Lab

m 03/2019 - Current

Ownership of project deliverables and translation of research into business applications.

PROJECT 4: Creation of interview and validated scoring measure for culture fit interview

Research Associate

Accenture PLC, Talent Innovation Lab

11/2018 - Promotion

Organizational behavior & evaluation research specialist.

- PROJECT 1: Statistical analysis for requirements of behavioral interview for future job candidates
- · PROJECT 2: Analysis of requirements for behavioral interview; initiated implementation plan with global management team
- PROJECT 3: Validated scoring measure for behavioral interview into pilot stage with global alignment teams

External Consultant

ICM Partners

1 09/2018 - 01/2019

% icmpartners.com

Part of a course-based project for large creative talent agency undergoing HR restructuring.

• 1-year development plan presented to CHRO with training cost savings projected to be \$10-\$15,000 per new hire.

Lecturer

Mount Saint Mary's University

1 01/2016 - 05/2018

% msmu.edu

Taught Research Methods, Social Psychology, and Organizational Psychology, with academic counseling.

EXPERIENCE

Clinical Psychologist Intern

Sovereign Health Group

1 08/2014 - 08/2015

Inpatient facility with individual and group therapy, psychological assessment, and internal consulting services.

· Assisted distribution of caseload to employees accounting for 25% increase in revenue and insurance billing.

EDUCATION

MA Organizational Behavior & Evaluation

Claremont Graduate University

• Emphasis in Business Administration

MA Clinical Psychology

Sofia University

Palo Alto, CA

BA

Naropa University

♀ Boulder, CO

SKILLS

Programming

R SPSS C++ Python LaTeX Java

Statistics

ANOVA Multiple Regression Social Network Analysis Psychometric Network Analysis

Categorical Data Analysis Non-Parametric Data Analysis